Hao Wang (Howie)

+434-227-8996 · howiewang2020@gmail.com · @howiework · howiework.com

PROFILE

Experienced web designer & developer with a background in architecture. Possessing well-honed design and development skills gained through a diverse background. Known for a keen eye for design, with professional experience using design tools, and adept at solving real-world problems through design thinking, research, and analytical skills.

KEY COMPETENCIES

UIUX / Agile / TestingReactFigma / AdobeXD / CanvaJavaScript (ES6)NodeJS / ExpressAdobe Creative Suite (PS, ID, IA)HTML 5 / CSSPython / ChatGPT / AIBilingual in Chinese and English

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

University of Virginia Comprehensive Cancer Center Multimedia Creative Professional II

Feb 2023 - Present

Promoted from contract web developer, I led the enhancement of the UVA Cancer Center website, enhancing aesthetics, functionality, and responsiveness. Crafting compelling content, collaborating with stakeholders, and managing timelines and performance metrics for ongoing improvement.

Codingheroes.io Feb 2024 - Present

Jonas' Newsletter Editor

Manage Jonas, a top Udemy instructor's newsletter with 86k subscribers and a remarkable 40% open rate. It's a bi-weekly digest for aspiring and seasoned web developers.

3Advance Dec 2022 - Jun 2023

Web Developer (contract)

Develop Boaturu's Admin & Renter sites with React, Next.js, Css-in-JS, Radix UI, Tailwind, and design AARP's EC Hub 2.0 Time Entry module using Figma & InVision, collaborating closely with teams and clients.

Rawle Murdy Associates Inc (BGRM)

Apr 2022 - Jul 2022

Web Developer (contract)

Work with web team to develop and enhance websites with complex integrations, APIs, animations, and functionality.

Sunwater Institute Mar 2022 - Apr 2022

Web Developer (contract)

Work on migrating source code for an institute platform product, coordinating with an overseas team and closely collaborating with local design and research teams.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

FrontendExpert Certificate

AlgoExpert

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Udemy Certifications *List link

University of Virginia

Master of Architecture

University of Mining and Technology

Bachelor of Architecture

SELECTED PROJECTS

Snap App

A photo-sharing platform for architecture enthusiasts; <u>video demo</u>; <u>process</u>; <u>code</u>

Lunch Break

A blog site on work-life balance; demo; code

NMAAHC

A mobile app (UIUX focused) for a museum

Howiework

Personal portfolio website using React